<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RecyclerView</string>

    <string name="new_content">
        Over 270 men, women and children have died as a result of a tri-train collision near Balasore in Odisha.
        As often happens after such tragedies, officials from the Railways and political leaders descended on the scene of the devastation
        and expressed shock,and spoke of sharing the grief. Commissions of enquiry and compensation to the families of the deceased were announced;
        treatment and relief to the injured were assured. But the people rightly expect much more than this. They have the right to demand safe travel from the government.
        But under the Modi government, that right has become difficult to guarantee.

        Railways continue to be among the most important means of transport for the vast majority of the people.
        India found its place on the railway map of the world in 1853, during British rule.
        Of course, the colonisers’ never intended to provide comfort for people: The introduction of the railways was intended
        mainly to facilitate speedy cargo movement. The British invested heavily in expanding the railway network in that period.
        Commenting on these developments, Karl Marx wrote in 1853 that by introducing railways and English education even though with the
        “vilest interests”, England became an “unconscious tool of history” in bringing about great social change. He was correct in his analysis,
        as these measures contributed to bringing the people of India closer and ﬁnally paved the way for strengthening the freedom movement.

        Independent India also witnessed the growth of the Railways. In 1947, the total length of railway lines was 54,000 km.
        Now, it has grown into a network of over 65,000 km, connecting all parts of the country. The impact of railways on our society also
        increased and trains became an integral part of life in India as the most aﬀordable mode of long-distance transport.

        India also witnessed a number of tragic rail accidents during this period. The Ariyalur train mishap in 1956 immediately comes to mind as
        it led to the resignation of the then Railway Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri. He took moral responsibility for the tragic accident,
        which claimed the lives of more than 140 people. Shastri is still remembered as a symbol of honesty, simplicity, probity and
        accountability in public life — values completely lacking in rulers of our times.

        In the aftermath of the Odisha tri-train accident, several questions are bound to emerge in the minds of the people.
        They are related to the policies and priorities of the Modi government.
    </string>
</resources>